The Parker Bailey Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Literary Writings, Series IV
  - Poetry, IV.A
    - Poetry by Parker Bailey, IV.A.1
      - [No title], 1962 Aug 1; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Poetry by Chauncey Roscoe Piety, IV.A.2
      - An Aeroplane Built for Two, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Arise, O Church of God, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - The Call to Worship, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Dates and Peaches, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Farewell, Okeeta, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - God is Everywhere, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
        1 autograph signed copy
      - God is in my Garden, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - God Longed for a Temple, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - God Make Me Worthy of Today, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Lead On, O Master Worker, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - O Christ, the Interpreter, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - O Master of all Minds, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Oh, Marvellous the Light, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Oh, the Teacher of the Mountain, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - The Old Salem Lovers, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Seek Ye the Kingdon Everlasting, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Worship the Spirit Everlasting, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Poetry by Other Authors, IV.A.3
      Arranged alphabetically by author. Within each entry, arranged alphabetically by title.
      - Children of God, no date; John Bowdler, Jr.; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 2)
        2 typed copies
      - I Saw Two Clouds, no date; Brainard, John G.C.; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Dies ist bestimmt, 1917; Braun, Otto; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Eros, 1913 Jun 10; Braun, Otto; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Über Graser und Halme, 1913 Aug 29; Braun, Otto; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Oh, London Town, no date; Dane, Clemence; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
        1 photocopy of newspaper clipping
      - I know a Quiet Stream, no date; Hinman, Charlton J.K.; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Snow--a Winter Sketch, no date; Hoyt, Ralph; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - To a Yellow Tulip, no date; Kattenhorn, George H.; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Easter, 1932, Easter; Jennings, Alice C.; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
        1 booklet of 5 poems
      - April Rain, no date; Loveman, Robert; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Dry Thine Eyes, 1932 Aug 2; McBride, Charles F.; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Eucharist, no date; Meehan, John; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - A Sumer's Dream, Meehan, John; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
        1 typed copy with autograph revisions
      - Ballade to Spring, no date; Neely, Sara Shelley; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Autumn Soliloquy, no date; Parker, Charles Edward; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - To Helen, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
        1 typed copy. Creator unknown, possibly Edgar Allan Poe.
      - Evening Prayer, no date; Scarlett, H. Campbell; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Falstaff's Song, no date; Stedman, Edmund Clarence; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
        1 typed copy (photocopy from Folder 1/13)
      - The Language of Music, no date; [No author given]; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
        1 typed copy with A last lines
      - Unto Thine Haven, no date; [No author given]; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Biographies and Program Notes, IV.B
    Arranged alphabetically by subject or title.
    - Bailey, Parker, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      1 short biography and list of published works
    - Koutzen, Boris, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Program Notes for PSuite, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Program Notes for 2-22-59, 2 items (Box 2, Folder 2)
      2 copies
    - Program Notes on John Perras, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - History of Musical Works by Parker Bailey, IV.C
    - Toccata-Ricercata-Finale for Organ, 14 items (Box 2, Folder 2)
      "Origin of the typed-R-F for Organ"
      4 typed copies
      1 autograph rough draft
      "Post-1933 Progress on the T-R-F"
      2 pages of untitled notes on the T-R-F
      2 additional copies of each of the above (4 p.)
      "The Two-Piano Adaptation of the T-R-F"
    - "Alexander"--arr. of gospel hymns as solos for Christian Science services, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
      "Origin of 'Alexander'..."
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano, 2 items (Box 2, Folder 2)
      "Origin of..."
      "Origin and 'Opus Career' of..."
- Miscellaneous Jottings and Papers, Series V
  - Includes: appointment cards, medical prescription, short notes, lists, financial calculations, notes for articles and essays, rough drafts for same and two complete articles: a. "Fortuitous Functionalism" and b. "L.L. Nunn, Pioneer", 1940-1976; 32 items (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Programs, Series VI
  - Programs Concerning Works by Parker Bailey, VI.A
    Arranged alphabetically by title, and chronologically within each entry.
    - Autumn Breezes, 1932 Oct 10; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 4)
      See also: Pastorale
    - Go Tell it on the Mountain (arr. by Parker Bailey), 1935 Dec 7; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Love's Frailty (Box 2, Folder 4)
      See: Memory
    - Memory, 1934-1936; 3 items (Box 2, Folder 4)
      1 copy of 4-29-34 program
      2 copies of 3-24-36 program
    - Mountain Twilight, 1932-1941; 4 items (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Nocturne, 1959-1960; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - O Bethlehem Beloved, 1935 Dec 29; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - O Christ, the Interpreter, 1928-1929; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Pastorale, 1932 Aug 14; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 4)
      See also: Music by Parker Bailey, Instrumental (X.A.1)--Pastorale
    - Pavane Mystique, 1931 May 22; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Prelude and Fugue (on the chorale "Wachet auf, ruft uns die Stimme"), 1941-1942; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Round of Folktunes, 1939-1942; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano, 1928-1946; 9 items (Box 2, Folder 4)
      3 copies of 5-15-28 program
      5 other program
      1 proof of 1 of above
    - Sonata for Violin and Piano, 1928 Nov 11; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - To a Yellow Tulip, 1931 May 31; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Toccata-Ricercata-Finale, 1933-1942; 15 items (Box 2, Folder 4)
      12 programs
      1 additional copy of 1 of above
      1 brochure for 1 of above programs
      1 extra page of program notes
    - Variations Symphoniques, 1930-1935; 5 items (Box 2, Folder 4)
      4 programs
      1 additional copy of 1-24-35 program
  - Programs Concerning Performances by Parker Bailey, VI.B
    - As soloist, 1921-1927; 4 items (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Arranged chronologically
    - As accompanist
      Arranged alphabetically by performer within each entry, arranged chronologically.
      - Hudson-Alexander, Caroline, (soprano), 1926-1929; 6 items (Box 2, Folder 5)
        5 programs
        1 brochure
      - Holmes, Harley (violinist), 1928 Nov 11; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Fuchs, Josef (violinist), 1930 Nov 11; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Programs Concerning Works by Horatio Parker, VI.C
    - Includes: Hora Novissima; selections from Mona; miscellaneous works, 1935-1964; 9 items (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Programs: Other Composers/Performers, VI.D
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 15 programs, 1928-1971; 17 items (Box 2, Folder 5)
      2 copies of 2 of above (Includes: works by Quincey Porter, Charles Ives, Douglas Moore, David Stanley Smith, Arthur Shepherd, Edward MacDowell and Fritz Kreisler; performances by Loesser and Rubinstein, Whittemore and Lowe, John Kirkpatrick, Frederick Bristol, Donna Lerew and Maria Stoesser, Anna Xydis, Leonard Bernstein, Louis Bagger and E.A. Kraft)
  - Miscellaneous Programs, VI.E
    - Includes: Parker Bailey's commencement exercises from high school and college, a Cleveland Orchestra brochure, notices from law firms and Century Association news letters, 1919-1973; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Newspaper Clippings, Series VII
  - Articles and Reviews Concerning Works by Parker Bailey, VII.A
    Arranged alphabetically by title of composition, chronologically within each entry.
    - Children of God
      See: O Christ, the Interpreter
    - Faith, 1929 Apr 11; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - O Christ, the Interpreter, no date; 3 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Orpheus with his Lute, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Pavane Mystique (for string quartet and piano), no date; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Prelude and Fugue (on the chorale "Wachet auf, ruft uns die Stimme"), 1940-1943; 12 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Round of Folktunes, 1942 Apr 28; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano, 1928; 5 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Sonata for Violin and Piano, 1928; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Toccata-Ricercata-Finale (on the-chorale "Singt dem Herrn eine neues Lied"), 1935-1939; 4 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Variations Symphoniques pour orgue (op. 4), 1939; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Winter Morn, 1942 Jan 28; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - [Unidentified Works], 1939; 3 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Articles and Reviews Concerning Performances by Parker Bailey, VII.B
    - As soloist, 1926-1928; 8 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
      See also: as accompanist (VII.B)
    - As accompanist, 1926-1929; 5 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Letters to the Editor, VII.C
    - Letters to the Editor, 1935-1965; 7 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Reviews, 1932-1933; VII.D
    - 14 reviews, 17 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
      (3) 1 copy each of 3 of the above
  - Articles Concerning Others, VII.E
    Three entire periodicals which do not directly concern Parker Bailey were not kept. They are all available in the Music Library's General Collection and their volume numbers have been noted on a sheet laid in Box 2, Folder 7.
    - Includes: Louis Bagger, Alban Berg, Ernest Bloch, Pablo Casals, Alicia De Larrocha, Werner Janssen, E.A. Kraft, Fritz Kreisler, Arthur Loesser, MacDowell Colony, Yehudi Menuhin, The Orchestra of America, Horatio Parker, Peoria Symphony Orchestra and String Trio, John Perras, Arthur Quimby, Arthur Shepherd, Melville Smith and Igor Stravinsky, 34 items (Box 2, Folder 7)
      See also: Articles and Reviews concerning works by Parker Bailey (VII.A) for Loesser Rubinstein and Arthur Quimby
  - Miscellaneous Articles of Interest, VII.F
    - 1958-1974, 18 items (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Originals of Marked Articles, VII.G
- Miscellaneous Bulletins, Reports And Brochures, Series VIII
  - General, 12 items (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Includes: Joseph H. Bearns Prize and Yale items
  - MacDowell Colony, 5 items (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Photographs and Pictures, Series IX
  - Photographs of Parker Bailey, 2 items (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 4 items (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Includes: C.R. Piety, Igor Stravinsky, Larry Schmidt
  - Photographs and Pictures, 3 items (Box 2, Folder 12)
    3 pages of notes
    - Originals of Marked Articles, 40 items (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Musical Works, Series X
  Numbering of pages is either that of the composer, or is by each sheet of paper (not each side). No distinction is made between the composer's pagination and that of the compiler of the register. Sketches in each entry are counted as (1) unless there is only one complete sketch (which is listed as "1") or unless they are set off in a special way (with attached notes, etc.)
  - Musical Works Composed by Parker Bailey, X.A
    - Instrumental, X.A.1
      Listed alphabetically by title of composition.
      - Autumn Breezes --for organ and piano, 4 items (Box 3, Folder 1)
        1 score (4 pp.); 35 cm. 1925
        Ink and pencil holograph
        (1) Sketches (15 pp.)
        2 pp. of notes
      - Autumn Song --for piano, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 1)
        1 score (2 pp.); 28 cm.
      - Bagatelle --for solo instrument and piano, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 1)
        1 score (2 pp.); 34 cm.
        With part (1 sheet) 22 x 25 cm.
        Negative photocopy
      - Bagatelle --for organ with optional piano part, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 1)
        1 score (5 pp.); 35 cm.
        (1) Sketches (4 pp.)
      - Boataroll, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 1)
        (1) Sketches (22 p.)
      - Canon at the Fifth --for violin, viola, and piano, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 1)
        1 score (1 p.); 22 x 25 cm.
        Pencil holograph
        1 set of parts (1 sheet each); 10 x 21 cm.
      - Fuga risvegliata (Box 3, Folder 1)
        See: Passacaglia concisa e contracreativa
      - Fugue, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 1)
        Ink holograph
      - Fugue, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Fugue, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Gigue, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 1)
        1 score (1 p.); 31 cm.
        (1) Sketches (3 pp.)
      - Invention, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 1)
        1 score (1 P.); 32 cm.
      - Memories --for piano, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 1)
        1 score (2 pp.); 32 cm
      - Midget Waltz --for piano, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 1)
        1 score (2 pp.); 28 ' cm.
      - Midsummer Barcarolle --for piano, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 1)
        1 score (3 pp.); 32 cm.
      - Mountain Twilight --for organ with optional piano part, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 1)
        2 scores (8 pp. each); 32 cm.
        Published H.W. Gray Co., Inc. 1937
      - Music is Beauty Adventuring --[for quartet?], 1 item (Box 3, Folder 1)
        1 sketch (3 pp.); 27 cm.
      - Passacaglia concisa e contracreativa and Fuga risvegliata, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 2)
        1 complete score of the Passacaglia
        (11 pp.); 26 by 36 cm.
        1 incomplete score of the Fugue
        (2 pp.); 26 by 36 cm.
      - Pastorale --for organ, 8 items (Box 3, Folder 2)
        1 score (6 pp.); 26 by 36 cm.
        1 score (5 pp.); 26 by 36 cm.
        1 incomplete score (2 pp.); 26 by 36 cm.
        Negative photocopies
        1 score (7 pp.); 35 cm.
        Ink holograph with piano obbligato
        1 set of sketches (9 pp.)
        1 note (1 p.)
        1 program attached to score
      - Pizzi-Trio, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 2)
        (1) Sketches (6 pp.)
      - Prelude and Fugue (on the Bach chorale "Wachet auf, ruft uns die Stimme")--for two pianos, 28 items (Box 3, Folder 3-7)
        1 score (32 pp.); 28 cm.
        Photographic prints and photocopies
        4 scores (28 pp.); 28 cm.
        Copies
        2 scores (28 pp.); 28 cm.
        Copies with corrections
        1 score (31 pp.); 28 cm.
        Photocopy and ink
        2 scores (27 pp.); 31 cm.
        (1) Incomplete copies (54 pp.)
        (1) Sketches (85 pp.)
        1 page of negative photographic copy
        1 score (2 pp.); 32 cm.
        Incomplete Ink holograph
        1 score (3 pp.); 33 cm.
        Incomplete negative photocopy
        1 score (10 pp.); 28 cm.
        4 sets of sketches (26 pp.)
        4 notes with above
      - Prelude and Fugue --arranged for organ, 3 items (Box 3, Folder 3-7)
        1 score (2 pp.) 26 by 36 cm.
        1 sketch (3 pp.)
        1 score (1 sheet); 17 cm.
        Negative copy of J.S. Bach's "Wachet auf"
      - Psuite Psychopathique --for piano, 3 items (Box 3, Folder 8)
        1 score (9 pp.); 32 cm.
        Photocopy of holograph
        1 score (6 pp.); 32 cm.
        Notes (4 pp.)
      - Quintet for Strings and Piano --D major, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 8)
        1 score (55 pp.); 35 cm.
      - Round of Folktunes, 10 items (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
        1 score (27 pp.); 31 cm.
        Copy of ink holograph
        Ink holograph transparencies
        2 scores (27 pp.); 32 cm.
        Copies of holograph
        2 scores (12 pp.); 32 cm.
        Pencil holographs with notes
        Early version
        1 score (14 pp.); 31 cm.
        Incomplete transparencies with note by Parker Bailey
        (1) Miscellaneous incomplete scores (12 pp.)
        (1) Sketches (50 pp.)
      - Rustic Dance --for solo instrument and piano, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 1)
        1 score (2 sheets); 35 cm.
        Negative photbcopy
        1 part (1 sheet); 22 by 24 cm.
      - 7-Up and Vodka --for piano--9 digits only, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Sonata --for solo instrument and piano, 5 items (Box 4, Folder 1)
        1 score (29 pp.); 33 cm.
        Copy of ink and pencil holograph
        1 part (1 sheet); 35 cm.
        Incomplete ink holograph
        1 copy of above
        1 sketch
      - Sonata for Flute and Piano, 30 items (Box 4, Folder 2-6)
        1 score (38 pp.); 32 cm.
        Published Schirmer (S.P.A.M.) 1929
        1 part (15 pp.); 32 cm.
        1 score ( 38 pp.); 31 cm.
        1 part (15 pp.); 31 cm.
        1 score (36 pp.); 31 cm.
        Published Theodore Presser, 1929
        1 list of publications
        1 score (38 pp.); 31 cm.
        Cut up--Published Schirmer, 1929
        1 score (13 pp.); 31 cm.
        Incomplete, cut up--Published Schirmer, 1929
        1 part (5 pp.); 31 cm.
        Incomplete, cut up--Schirmer, 1929
        1 score (38 pp.); 28 cm.
        Cut up--Published Theodore Presser, 1957 (renewed)
        1 part (15 pp.); 28 cm.
        Cut up--Presser, 1957 (renewed)
        2 photocopied sheets
        1 set of negative prints (53 pp.); 26 cm.- complete
        With corrections--Published Schirmer, 1929
        With corrections--Schirmer, 1929
        Photocopy
        4 notes (3 autographs)
        1 score (16 pp.); 26 cm.
        Incomplete photographic prints
        1 score (4 pp.); 35 cm.
        Incomplete holograph
        1 photocopied sheet
        1 score (4 pp.); 31 cm.
        Incomplete--Published Schirmer, 1929
        (1) Sketches (21 pp.)
        1 engraved plate (28 cm.)
        2 notes
      - Song from Afar --for piano, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 7)
        1 score 1.2 pp.); 28 cm.
      - Squirrel Cage --for piano, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Suite for Flute, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 7)
        1 score (21 pp.); 34 cm.
        1 part (7 pp.); 32 cm.
        (1) Sketches (70 pp.)
      - Toccata-Ricercata-Finale --for organ, 14 items (Box 4, Folder 8)
        2 scores (16 pp.); 31 cm.
        Published H.W. Gray, 1958
        1 score (12 pp.); 26 by 36 cm.
        Negative photocopy of holograph
        1 score (11 pp.); 26 by 36 cm.
        4 programs (attached to above score)
        1 score (16 pp.); 32 cm.
        Negative proof with corrections
        1 score (12 pp.); 24 by 31 cm.
        Ink and pencil holograph with corrections
        1 score (3 pp.); 26 by 36 cm.
        Incomplete ink and pencil holograph
        See also: Programs (VI), Music by Others (X.E)--Bach's "Vierstimmiges Choralgesänges," Literary Writings--History of Works (IV.C), and Personal Correspondence (I.C)--Parker Bailey's letter to Dean, 7-2-34
      - Toccata-Ricercata-Finale --for 2 pianos, 10 items (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
        2 scores (31 pp.); 32 cm.
        Ink and pencil holographs
        1 score (17 pp.); 31 cm.
        1 score (19 pp.); 31 cm.
        Incomplete ink holograph transparencies
        1 score (15 pp.); 35 cm.
        Photocopies with note
        (1) Sketches (57 pp.)
        1 note
      - Un Bel Di di Campogiovanni, 9 items (Box 5, Folder 3)
        2 scores (2 pp.); 32 cm.
        Pencil holographs
        1 score (2 pp.); 29 cm.
        3 copies of first page of score
        (1) Sketches (5 pp.)
        See also: Bulletins (VIII)--International Library Bulletin.
      - Variations Symphoniques --for organ, 3 items (Box 5, Folder 3)
        2 scores (8 pp.); 35 cm.
        Published À la Flûte de Pan, 1937
        1 score (10 pp.); 22 by 29 cm.
        Vocal--Solo Voice
    - Vocal--Solo Voice, X.A.2
      - Ballade To Spring, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 4)
        (Text by Sara Shelley Neely)
      - Children of God, 4 items (Box 5, Folder 4)
        (Text by John Bowdler)
        1 score (5 pp.); 32 cm.
        2 scores (4 pp.); 31 by 35 cm.
        Photocopies of holograph
        1 score (4 pp.); 30 cm.
      - Days Forget, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 4)
        (Text by Ethel Vera King)
        1 score (4 pp.); 33 cm.
      - Dry Thine Eyes, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 4)
        (Text by Charles F. McBride)
      - Evening Prayer, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 4)
        (Text by Campbell Scarlett)
        1 score (4 pp.); 32 cm.
        See also: Choral Music by Parker Bailey (X.A.3)--Vesper Prayer (SATB)
      - Faith (Box 5, Folder 4)
        See: Four Songs for High Voice
      - Four Songs for High Voice --with pianoforte, 15 items
        1 score (7 pp.); 34 cm.
        (1) Sketches (2 pp.)
        - "She is Not Fair" (Box 5, Folder 4)
          (Text by Hartley Coleridge)
        - "Winter Morn" (Box 5, Folder 4)
          (Text by Ralph Hoyt)
          2 scores (4 pp.); 31 cm.
          Published H.W. Gray Co., 1937
        - "Winter Morn" (Box 5, Folder 4)
          3 scores (2 pp.); 35 cm.
          2 scores (2 pp.); 34 cm.
        - "Faith" (Box 5, Folder 4)
          (Text by George H. Kattenhorn)
        - "To a Yellow Tulip" (Box 5, Folder 4)
          (Text by Kattenhorn)
          2 scores (2 pp.); 32 cm and 29 cm
          2 scores (2 pp.); 35 cm.
      - God is Singing, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 4)
        (Text by Chauncey Roscoe Piety)
        2 scores (5 pp.); 31 cm.
        Published Oliver Ditson Co., 1940
      - God Longed for a Temple, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 4)
        (Text by C.R. Piety)
        1 Sketch
        See also: Personal Correspondence, General (I.A)--12-11-46 letter from C.R. Piety
      - Great Heart of God, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 4)
        2 scores (3 pp.); 30 cm.
        Negative photocopies of holographs
      - I Saw Two Clouds, 4 items (Box 5, Folder 4)
        (Text adapted from J.G.C. Brainard)
        4 scores (4 pp.); 35 cm.
        Ink holograms with corrections
      - Let the Words of My Mouth, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 4)
        (Author of text unknown)
      - Love's Frailty, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 4)
        (Text from "The Way of the World" by William Congreve)
        Ink holograph transparency
      - Memory, 6 items (Box 5, Folder 5)
        (Text by John Meehan)
        2 scores (2 pp.); 32 by 35 cm.
        2 scores (2 pp.); 29 by 33 cm.
        See also: Choral Music composed by Parker Bailey (X.A.3)--Memory
      - O Christ, the Interpreter, 5 items (Box 5, Folder 5)
        1 sketch (1 sheet)
        2 scores (4 pp.); 36 by 31 cm.
        Photocopies with ink and pencil markings
      - She is Not Fair (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Solace, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Summer is Singing, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 5)
        1 score (1 p.); 23 by 31 cm.
      - A Summer's Dream, 4 items (Box 5, Folder 5)
        1 score (5 pp.); 30 cm.
        Photocopy of printed version
        1 score (5 pp.); 32 cn-.
        Negative -photocopy of above
        Pencil and ink holograph
      - Take Time to be Holy (with Hugh Alexander), 2 items (Box 5, Folder 5)
        score (4 pp.); 32 cm.
        Ink holograph--keyboard only
      - Tell Me, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 5)
        1 score (2 pp.); 31 cm.
        Photocopy of above
      - To a Yellow Tulip (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Under the Window, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 5)
        1 score (1 sheet); 34 cm.
      - Unto Thine Haven, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 5)
        1 score (4 pp.); 26 cm.
        Pencil holograph with corrections
      - Vorfrühling, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 5)
        (Text by Herbert Schaumann)
      - Widmung, 3 items (Box 5, Folder 5)
        (text by Herbert Schaumann)
        Copy
        (1) sketches (2 sheets)
      - Winter Morn (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Zwielicht, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 5)
        Vocal--Choral
    - Vocal--Choral, X.A.3
      Alphabetically by title of composition. For SATB unless otherwise noted.
      - Adoremus Dominum, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 6)
        2 scores (1 sheet); 15 by 25 cm.
      - An April Morning (SSA), 2 items (Box 5, Folder 6)
        (Text by Bliss Carman)
        2 scores (6 pp.); 27 cm.